荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   为万世开百事
翻译   陌客之子
翻译   Rubilacxe
君临 King's Landing
翻译   凯冯拉拉兄控
红堡
Red Keep
校对   pksunking
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
校对   北落师门
临冬城
Winterfell
后期    poplar
监制    临冬城的狮子
绝境长城 the Wall
策划    baozhenyuawabi
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第十集   The Children
森林之子
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
曼斯·雷德
“塞外之王”
你又披上了黑袍
You're wearing a black cloak again.
他们派我前来与你谈判
I've been sent to negotiate with you.
似乎我轻信的天性又一次占了上风
It appears my trusting nature got the better of me.
这也不是第一次了
It's happened before.
琼恩·雪诺 我多希望当时你向我们宣誓时是忠诚的
I was hoping your loyalty was real when you pledged yourself to us, Jon Snow.
真的 非常希望
Truly I was.
断掌科林命我加入你的军队
The Halfhand ordered me to join your army
然后把收集到的一切信息带回黑城堡
and bring back whatever information I could to Castle Black.
他让我杀了他以便获得你们的信任
He made me kill him so you'd trust me.
我的确忠于他……
I was loyal...
我忠于科林与守夜人的誓言
to him and to my Night's Watch vows.
所有誓言吗？
All your vows?
她还不足以改变你 对吗？
She wasn't enough to turn you, eh?
那你足以改变她吗？
Were you enough to turn her?
我离开时 她向我
She put three arrows in me
射了三箭
when I escaped.
你在黑城堡与她重逢了吗？
Did you see her again at Castle Black?
- 是的 - 然后呢？
- Yes. - And?
她死了
She's dead.
- 是你干的？ - 不
- Your doing? - No.
我们应当敬她一杯
We'll drink to her.
我有千万种方法可以杀了你
Of all the ways I'd kill you,
还不至于要下毒
poison would be the last.
- 敬耶哥蕊特 - 敬耶哥蕊特
- Ygritte. - Ygritte.
这不是葡萄酒
That's not wine.
不 这是北境人喝的酒 琼恩·雪诺
No, it's a proper northern drink, Jon Snow.
你们干的很好 战斗得很顽强
You did well. Fought hard.
有几个我们最强壮的战士也被你们杀了
Killed some of our strongest men.
我们的一位巨人进入了你们的地道
One of our giants went into your tunnel
再也没出来
and never came out again.
强壮的玛格
Mag the Mighty.
他死了
He's dead.
他杀了我的朋友葛兰
He killed my friend Grenn.
他是巨人国王
He was their king.
他的血脉可以追溯到先民到达之前
The last of a bloodline that stretches back
他是硕果仅存的一位
before the First Men.
葛兰来自一个小农庄
Grenn came from a farm.
- 敬玛格与葛兰 - 敬葛兰与玛格
- Mag and Grenn. - Grenn and Mag.
科柏克 能拿点吃的来吗？
Kullback, could I trouble you for something to eat?
我觉得我的客人可能有相当一段时间
I don't imagine our guest has eaten anything
没吃东西了吧
for quite some time.
所以 你是来和我谈条件的？
So, you're here to strike a bargain?
撤走军队 回家去吧
Turn your army around and go home.
你知道我很清楚你们的弓箭不多了
You know I know you're low on arrows,
燃油不多了 人也不多了
you're low on oil, you're low on men.
你们还剩多少人？有五十个吗？
How many are left, 50?
我告诉托蒙德和欧瑞尔了
I told Tormund and Orell.
我们有一千多名战士
We have more than 1,000 men.
我把一切毫无保留的展示给你
I showed you everything I had.
我们十万人的大军
The whole army, 100,000 strong.
然而你做了什么？你利用所知道的一切攻击我们
And what did you do? You fired on us with everything you had.
可这并不算什么 我发现你背叛后
It wasn't much. As soon as I saw that,
立即调派了四百名勇士攀登城墙
I sent 400 men to climb the Wall,
从这儿向西五英里 有一段无人看守的区域
an unmanned stretch five miles west of here.
他们中许多人会死在攀登途中
A lot of them will die climbing,
然而今夜之后大部分勇士就将到达长城背后
but most of them will be over by the end of the day.
琼恩·雪诺 我对你十分诚实
It's me being honest with you, Jon Snow,
你对我可从来不这么坦诚
which is more than you've ever done for me.
我的人民已流得够多血了
My people have bled enough.
我们并不是来征服一切的
We're not here to conquer.
我们只希望躲到你们的长城后面
We're here to hide behind your Wall.
和你们一样 我们需要你们的地道
Just like you. We need your tunnel.
我们都知道凛冬将至
Now we both know that winter is coming.
如果我的人民不能在严冬到达之前迁入长城南面
And if my people aren't south of the Wall when it comes in earnest,
我们的下场比死还不如
we'll all end up worse than dead.
你希望和我们谈条件？
You want to strike a bargain with me?
我的条件很简单
Here's the bargain.
你回去 打开城门
You go back, you open the gates to us,
我向你保证再不会有人死去
and I swear to you that no one else will die.
如果你拒绝
Refuse,
我们将屠尽黑城堡里所有的人
and we'll kill every last man at Castle Black.
啊！
Ah!
哦 这才是你的本意
Oh, that's why you're here.
我承认如果你动手的话他们来不及阻止你
I reckon you could do it before any of them could stop you.
当然 之后他们就会杀了你
They'd kill you, of course.
他们会慢慢虐杀你
They'd kill you slow.
不过你走进帐篷的时候就知道这一点了
But you knew that when you came in here.
你觉得你能下得了手吗 琼恩·雪诺？
Are you capable of that, Jon Snow?
在帐篷主人主动议和时刺杀他？
Killing a man in his own tent when he's just offered you peace?
守夜人就这点能耐？
Is that what the Night's Watch is?
你就这点能耐？
Is that what you are?
有骑士冲过来了！
Riders coming!
- 你想趁和谈时突袭我们吗？ - 不
- Are you attacking us? - No.
正如你所说 我们没有兵力突袭
It's like you said, we don't have the men.
守住！ 集合！ 集合！
Hold! To me! To me!
放下武器！
Stand down!
我说过我的人民已流够血了
I said my people have bled enough
这绝非虚言
and I meant it.
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士” 史坦尼斯的首相
把他们赶到一起
Round them up.
别下马
Stay with the horses.
你就是塞外之王？
You're the King-beyond-the-Wall?
- 你知道我是谁吗？ - 未闻阁下大名
- Do you know who I am? - Never had the pleasure.
这是史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
This is Stannis Baratheon,
七大王国唯一正统的国王
the one true king of the Seven Kingdoms.
我们并不在七大王国的疆界内 你的衣着可不适合这儿的天气
We're not in the Seven Kingdoms and you're not dressed for this weather.
向国王投降时下跪是基本礼仪
It is customary to kneel when surrendering to a king.
自由民从不屈膝
We do not kneel.
夜幕降临前我手下会有上千名你的子民
I'll have thousands of your men in chains by nightfall,
我们没有住宿安置他们 也没有食物喂养他们
have nowhere to put them, have nothing to feed them.
我并不想屠杀无用的落水狗
I'm not here to slaughter beat dogs.
他们的命运由他们的国王决定
Their fate depends on their king.
悉听尊便 我们绝不屈膝
All the same, we do not kneel.
把他们带走
Take these men away.
一个守夜人跑到野人的帐篷里来干什么？
What's a man of the Night's Watch doing in a wildling camp?
他们派我前来与塞外之王谈判
I was sent to discuss terms with the King-beyond-the-Wall.
年轻人 你正与王国唯一的正统国王交谈
You're speaking to the one true king, boy.
你需要尊称他为陛下
You will address him as Your Grace.
我知道他是正统国王 我父亲为他而死
I know he's the king. My father died for him.
陛下 我的名字是琼恩雪诺
My name is Jon Snow, Your Grace.
我是奈德·史塔克的儿子
I'm Ned Stark's son.
你父亲是一位值得尊敬的人
Your father was an honorable man.
正如你所言 陛下
He was, Your Grace.
你认为他会如何处置野人头目呢？
What do you think he'd have done with him?
我曾是他的阶下囚
I was this man's prisoner once.
他本可虐待我或杀死我
He could have tortured me. He could have killed me.
可他饶了我一命
But he spared my life.
我认为我父亲会将他囚禁起来
I think my father would have taken him prisoner,
听听他会怎么说
listened to what he had to say.
好吧 那么把他关起来
Very well, then. Take him.
陛下
Your Grace.
如果我父亲看到了我所经历的事情
If my father had seen the things that I've seen,
他一定会建议您在夜幕降临之前焚毁尸体
he'd also tell you to burn the dead before nightfall.
所有尸体
All of them.
科本
被剥夺项链的学士
我会建议用点罂粟花奶 减轻他的痛苦
I would suggest milk of the poppy
可他已经彻底麻木了
to ease his pain, but he is completely insensate.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
可恶的马泰尔家族
Bloody Martells.
这似乎是狮身蝎尾兽毒
The cause appears to be manticore venom.
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
嗯 是的 死神之首 狮身蝎尾兽
It is. The Death's Head manticore.
派席尔
大学士
我曾阅读过许多相关书籍
Yes, I've read a great deal about it.
这是种非常恐怖的毒液
It's a horrible poison.
往往来自于曼达利
Usually Mantari in origin.
哦！是啊是啊
Oh! Yes, yes.
已经回天乏术了
There's nothing to be done.
不 也许还有救
Yes, there is.
我能请问一下阁下这是在做什么吗？
May I ask what you think you're doing?
拯救他
Saving him.
陛下 我很希望我们能有其他选择
Your Grace, I wish it were otherwise,
不过格雷果爵士已经无药可救了
but Ser Gregor is beyond saving.
远非人力能及
Well, well beyond.
这家伙连学士都不是
This man is not even a maester,
竟在这里充起大学士来了
let alone Grand Maester.
幸好如此
That's for the best.
学士们才不知道如何拯救他呢
No maester knows how to save him.
正是因为他如此傲慢
That is exactly the sort of arrogance
学城才决定开除他的 陛下
that had him expelled from the Citadel, Your Grace.
他所谓的好奇心违背自然 异常危险
His curiosity was deemed dangerous and unnatural.
我认为开除他真是明智的决定
Rightly so, in my opinion.
大学士 你可以离开了
You're dismissed, Grand Maester.
陛下 这可是我的实验室
But, Your Grace, this is my laboratory.
- 现在不是了 - 可我……
- Not anymore. -  But I--
- 你能救他吗？ - 很难说 陛下
- You can save him? - Difficult to say, Your Grace.
但如果我过去的成果能派得上用场……
But if my past work is any guide...
……我们也许有希望
...we stand a chance.
尽你一切力量救他
Do everything you can.
需要什么都请告诉我
Come to me for anything you need.
谢谢陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
不过您得知道
You should know,
这一过程或许会让他……
the process may change him...
有点变化。
somewhat.
会使他变弱吗？
Will it weaken him?
哦绝不会
Oh, no.
那就够了
Very well, then.
够了
Not another word.
我们已经讨论过这个 事情已经敲定了
We've been over this. The matter's closed.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
可我想再谈一谈
I'm opening it again.
你已经与洛拉斯·提利尔订婚
You were betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
眼下便是他的未婚妻
You're still betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
等到托曼和玛格丽成婚时
And you will marry Loras Tyrell
便是洛拉斯·提利尔迎娶你之日
as soon as Tommen marries Margaery.
我不会嫁给他
I will not.
詹姆不能结婚 也不能继承领土
Jaime cannot marry or inherit lands.
提利昂的判决明天就要执行
Tyrion's sentence will be carried out tomorrow.
你曾经多次声称
You have on several occasions made great claims
愿为家族做出一切
about your commitment to this family's future.
而现在 你对这个家族
Your role in that future
比以往任何时候都重要
is more vital now than it ever was.
我不在乎
I don't care.
君临才是我的归宿，我要跟我儿子一起留在这里，他才是国王
I will stay in King's Landing where I belong with my son the king.
在你九岁那年 我被命令前往首都
When you were nine years old, I was called to the capital.
当时我决定带上你的弟弟 而不是你
I decided to take your brother with me and not you.
你却坚持无论在什么情况下
You insisted that you would not be left at Casterly Rock
自己都不能被留在凯岩城 如果你还记得——
under any circumstances. And if you recall--
我没有兴趣听你在这里洋洋自得
I'm not interested in hearing another one of your smug stories
复述你上次是怎么赢得争论的
about the time you won.
这次我不会再听你的摆布
This isn't going to be one of those times.
你以为你会是第一个
Do you think you'll be the first person
被强行拖到教堂成婚的人么？
dragged into a sept to be married against her will?
你那时大步踏入王座厅
When you marched into the throne room to tell me
告诉我我们赢得了黑水河之战——你还记得么？
we'd won the Battle of Blackwater-- do you remember?
当时我和托曼坐在铁王座上
I was sitting on the Iron Throne with Tommen.
我已经准备好喂他服下夜影之水
I was about to give him essence of nightshade.
一想到那些恶棍会把我的儿子夺走
That's how far I was willing to go when I thought
我什么都做得出来
someone awful had come to take my son away.
而现在 又有些恶棍要来把他夺走
Someone awful is coming to take him away.
- 不 - 乔佛里死了
- No. - Joffrey is dead.
弥赛菈像家畜一样被卖了出去
Myrcella's been sold like livestock.
而你现在想把我送到高庭去 偷走我的孩子
And now you want to ship me off to Highgarden and steal my boy.
我最后的孩子
My last boy.
玛格丽会把爪子伸出来
Margaery will dig her claws in,
你也会把爪子伸出来 你们会像野兽一样
you will dig your claws in and you'll fight over him
争夺他 直到把他撕成两半
like beasts until you rip him apart.
在此之前 我宁可先毁了我们的家族
I will burn our house to the ground before I let that happen.
你想做什么？
And how will you do that?
我要将真相公之于众
I'll tell everyone the truth.
什么真相？
What truth would that be?
你不知道 是么？
You don't know, do you?
你从来不肯相信
You never believed it.
这怎么可能呢？
How is that possible?
我在说什么呢？这当然有可能
What am I saying? Of course it's possible.
一个如此着魔于自己理想中家族理念的人
How can someone so consumed by the idea of his family
又怎么会对家族里真正发生的事情有一点概念呢？
have any conception what his actual family was doing?
我们当初就在你眼皮子底下 而你却视而不见
We were right there in front of you and you didn't see us.
过去二十年里如果你看过一眼
One look in the past 20 years,
认真看一眼你自己的孩子们 你就该知道
one real look at your own children and you would have known.
知道什么？
Known what?
他们说的都是真的
Everything they say is true.
- 詹姆和我的事 - 不
- About Jaime and me. - No.
- 你所谓的千秋家业就是个笑话  - 不 不 不 不
- Your legacy is a lie. - No, no, no, no.
我不相信你的话
I don't believe you.
不 你相信
Yes, you do.
詹姆
Jaime.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
你赢了
You won.
又少了一个弟弟 你一定很自豪吧
One fewer brother. Must be proud of yourself.
没有什么事情你做不出来的 是吧？
There's really nothing you wouldn't do, is there?
为了我的家族 没有
For my family, no, nothing.
你无法想象我能为了家族做出什么事
I would do things for my family you couldn't imagine.
- 提利昂是你的家人 - 他不是
- Tyrion is your family. - He's not.
- 这件事你无法选择 - 我可以 你也一样
- You don't get to choose. - I do. So do you.
你可以选择那个降生时害死我们母亲的东西——
You can choose the creature that killed our mother to come into this world--
你真的疯到认为他要为此负责？
Are you really mad enough to blame him for that?
他没有想要害死她 他只是个婴儿
He didn't decide to kill her. He was an infant.
疾病也没有想要杀死任何人
A disease doesn't decide to kill you.
可你还是会在这之前把它除去
All the same, you cut it out before it does.
你想要的是什么？你选择什么？
What do you decide? What do you choose?
我为了回到你身边做的那些事
The things I did to get back to you,
为了找回你而承受的痛苦——
to endure all that, only to find you--
我选择你
I choose you.
- 你不过是说说 - 不
- Those are words. - Yes.
就像我刚跟父亲说的一样
Like the ones I just said to Father.
我告诉他了
I told him.
告诉他什么？
Told him what?
关于我们的事
I told him about us.
你告诉他了？
You told him?
我告诉他我不会嫁给洛拉斯•提利尔
I told him I won't marry Loras Tyrell.
我告诉他我要呆在这里 跟托曼在一起 和你在一起
I told him I'm staying right here with Tommen, with you.
你认为他会就这么接受这个决定？
You think he'll just accept that?
去问他吧
Go and ask him.
你说了什么？
What did you say?
我不想再谈论泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't want to talk about Tywin Lannister.
我没有选择泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't choose Tywin Lannister.
我不爱泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't love Tywin Lannister.
我爱我的弟弟
I love my brother.
我爱我的爱人
I love my lover.
别人会说闲话 会嘲笑我们
People will whisper, they'll make their jokes.
随他们去
Let them.
他们都那么渺小 我甚至看不到他们
They're all so small, I can't even see them.
我只看到最重要的
I only see what matters.
也许有人会进来
Someone will walk in.
我不管
I don't care.
你正站在“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝
不焚者
弥林女王
安达尔人 洛伊拿人和先民的女王
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
大草原的“卡丽熙”
镣铐破除者和龙之母的面前
感谢您召见我 女王陛下
我的名字是费内兹
如果您需要的话 我也可以说通用语
I can speak the common tongue if you wish.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
“无畏的” 女王铁卫
你说得非常好
You speak it very well.
在您给我自由前 我属于米格达尔伟主
Before you freed me, I belonged to Master Mighdal.
我是他孩子们的导师
I was tutor to his children.
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
我教导他们语言和历史
I taught them languages and history.
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
因为我 他们对您的家族非常了解
They know a great deal about your family because of me.
小卡拉只有七岁
Little Calla is only seven,
但她非常仰慕您
but she admires you very much.
我希望我能配得上她的仰慕
I hope I can prove worthy of her admiration.
我能为你做什么？
What can I do for you?
您占领城市时 孩子们乞求我
When you took the city, the children begged me
不要离开他们的家
not to leave the house.
可米格达尔伟主和我都认为我必须离开
But Master Mighdal and I agreed that I must.
所以我无家可归
So I lost my home.
现在只能睡在街上
Now I live on the streets.
我安排了食堂和棚屋
I have outfitted mess halls
给曾经的奴隶提供伙食和住宿
to feed all former slaves and barracks to shelter them.
我无意冒犯 女王陛下
I do not mean to offend, Your Grace.
我去过那些地方
I went to one of these places.
年轻人欺压老者
The young prey on the old.
随意抢夺想要的东西 还殴打反抗者
Take what they want and beat us if we resist.
我的无垢者会尽快恢复秩序保证安全
My Unsullied will make them safe again in short order,
朋友 我向你保证
my friend, this I promise you.
即使那些地方安全了 我在那儿算什么？
Even if they are safe, who would I be there?
我生活的目标是什么？
What purpose would I serve?
在我的主人家里 我是一个老师
With my master, I was a teacher.
他的孩子们尊敬我 爱戴我
I had the respect and love of his children.
你到底想要什么？
What is it that you want from me?
女王陛下 我请求您
Your Grace, I ask you
让我把自己卖回给米格达尔伟主
to let me sell myself back to Master Mighdal.
你想回到拥有你的人那里
You want to return to a man who owned you
像他拥有的一只山羊 一把椅子一样？
like a goat or a chair?
我向您请求 女王陛下
Please, Your Grace.
年轻人也许会在您为他们建立的新世界里欣喜若狂
The young may rejoice in the new world you have built for them,
但我们这些经受不住变化的老家伙
but for those of us too old to change,
却只能在这个世界里恐惧而凄惨地活着
there is only fear and squalor.
这样想的不止我一个
I am not alone.
外面还有很多人等着向您请求同样的事情
There are many outside waiting to beg the same of you.
我解放了这里的人民
I did not take this city to preside
并不是为了给他们套上同样的枷锁
over the injustice I fought to destroy.
我占领这里是为了给人民带来自由
I took it to bring people freedom.
但自由意味着由你自己做决定
But freedom means making your own choices.
我允许你与你之前的主人签订合同
I will allow you to sign a contract with your former master.
但合同的期限不能超过一年
It may not cover a period lasting longer than a year.
谢谢 女王陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢
Thank you.
伟主们会利用这一点钻空子
The masters will take advantage of this situation.
那些为他们服务的人
The men serving them
实际上还是奴隶
will be slaves in all but name.
靠近些 朋友
Approach, my friend.
我听不懂 女王陛下
女王陛下说你可以靠近点
我带来了——
I have brought you--
他从天上飞来
He came from the sky.
黑色的那只
The black one.
有翼的黑影
The winged shadow.
他从天上飞来 然后……
He came from the sky and...
我的女儿
My girl.
我的小女儿
My little girl.
她叫什么名字？
What was her name?
她叫扎拉 陛下
Zala, Your Grace.
- 她几岁？ - 三岁
- How old was she? - Three.
三岁
Three.
还没有卓耿的消息吗？
有船员三天前看到它在黑色大峭壁附近飞翔 女王陛下
在这之后就没有消息了
去地底墓室见我
雷哥
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的龙
韦赛利昂
他们中有的来自白港和荒冢屯
They came to us from White Harbor and Barrowton,
也有的来自美人市集和君临
from Fairmarket and King's Landing,
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人学士
从北到南
from north and south,
从东到西
from east and west.
他们为保护男女老少而死
They died protecting men, women, and children
身后却籍没无闻
who will never know their names.
我们应铭记他们
It is for us to remember them.
铭记我们的兄弟
Our brothers,
我们将难得再见如此之人
we shall never see their like again.
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人
前都城守备队队长
他们的守望至死方休 于斯结束
And now their watch is ended.
赛丽丝·佛罗伦
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩之王后
希琳·拜拉席恩
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的女儿
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
梅丽珊卓
光之王的“红袍祭司”
你们那瞎老头给我包扎了伤口
Your old blind man patched me up.
为什么？
Why?
他宣誓医治所有伤员 无论敌友
He's sworn to treat all wounded men, friend or foe.
你要我活着 好慢慢折磨我？
You want me alive so you can torture me?
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人
没人会折磨你
No one's gonna torture you.
那么我们会怎么死？吊死？砍头？
So how do we die? Hanging? Beheading?
从长城上扔下去？
Drop us from the top of the Wall?
我不知道他们会怎么对囚犯
I don't know what happens to the prisoners.
谁说了算？
Who decides?
我猜是史坦尼斯
I suppose Stannis does.
他现在成你国王了？
He your king now?
我没有国王
I don't have a king.
你跟我们在一起待得太久 琼恩·雪诺
You spent too much time with us, Jon Snow.
再也不是下跪之人了
You can never be a kneeler again.
我们要把你们那边的死尸也烧了
We're gonna burn the bodies of your dead.
你有什么话要对他们说的吗？
Do you want to say any words over them?
话？什么话？
Words? What kind of words?
悼词 我不知道你们自由民是怎么送别死者的
Funeral words. I don't know how the free folk do it.
那有什么用？
Do what?
说声再见
Say farewell.
死人是听不见的 小子
The dead can't hear us, boy.
雪诺
Snow.
你爱她吗？
Did you love her?
她爱着你
She loved you.
她告诉你的？
She told you?
不
No.
她一直念叨着要亲手宰了你
All she ever talked about was killing you.
所以我知道
That's how I know.
她属于北方
She belongs in the North.
真正的北方
The real North.
你懂吗？
You understand me?
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
夏天
布兰·史塔克的冰原狼
阿多
临冬城的马僮
玖健·黎德
拥有绿之视野的男孩
梅拉·黎德
布兰·史塔克的保护者
我们可以停一停 我们可以休息一下
We can stop. We can rest.
我们找到三眼乌鸦再休息
We'll rest with the three-eyed raven.
布兰·史塔克
易形者
我们撑不住的
We're not going to make it.
我们已经到了
We're already here.
玖健
Jojen.
看呐 玖健 快看
Look, Jojen. Look.
玖健！坚持住！
Jojen! Come on!
去帮他们！快！
Help them! Now!
抓紧我！
Hold on to me!
坚持住！
Hang on!
- 阿多 - 去帮他们！
- Hodor. - Help them!
阿多
Hodor.
阿多！
Hodor!
阿多
Hodor.
阿多！
Hodor!
布兰！
Bran!
快！救你自己！
Save yourself, now!
随我来 布兰登·史塔克
Come with me, Brandon Stark.
他已去了
He is lost.
随我们来 要么就随他而死
Come with me or die with him.
跟他们走
Go with them.
他们没法追来
They cannot follow us.
那些驱役他们的力量在这里无能为力
The power that moves them is powerless here.
你是谁？
Who are you?
先民叫我们森林之子
The First Men called us the children,
但我们早在他们之前就已存在了
but we were born long before them.
来 他正等着你呢
Come, he waits for you.
您就是三眼乌鸦？
You're the three-eyed raven?
三眼乌鸦
绿先知
我有过诸多经历
I've been many things.
现在的我是这副模样
Now I am what you see.
我弟弟 他带领我们前来 现在却——
My brother, he led us to you and now he--
他知道会发生什么
He knew what would happen.
从他动身的那一刻就知道
From the moment he left,
但他依然决意前来
he knew and he went anyway.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我一直注视着你们
I've been watching you.
用我的一千零一只眼睛
All of you.
注视着你们所有人
All of your lives.
所有人的命运
With 1,000 eyes and one.
现在你终于找到我了
Now you've come to me at last,
布兰登·史塔克
Brandon Stark.
尽管有些晚
Though the hour is late.
我不想要任何人为我而死
I didn't want anyone to die for me.
借助他的死 你才能找回自己失去的东西
He died so you could find what you have lost.
您要治好我的腿吗？
You're going to help me walk again?
你永远也无法行走了
You will never walk again.
但你可以飞
But you will fly.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
波德瑞克
Podrick.
马哪儿去了？
Where are the horses?
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
我昨晚把它们栓好了
I hobbled them last night.
怎么栓的？
What sort of hobble?
8字形 就像您教我的那样
A figure eight like you taught me.
你要真按我教的做了
If you did it like I taught you,
马就不会丢
then the horses would be here.
也许是被偷了？
Thieves, maybe?
从这儿到鹰巢城起码还有三十里
It's at least 30 miles to the Eyrie from here.
你扛着鞍囊吧
You're carrying the saddlebags.
艾莉亚·史塔克
有人来了
People coming.
先憋着屎 有人来了
You can shit later. There's people coming.
早安
Morning.
我喜欢你的剑
I like your sword.
我们快到血门了吗？
Are we getting close to the Bloody Gate?
还有差不多十里
About 10 more miles.
听见了吗 波德瑞克？
Did you hear that, Podrick?
还有十里就到血门了
Only 10 more miles to the Bloody Gate.
你是骑士吗？
Are you a knight?
不
No.
但你会使剑？
But you know how to use that sword?
我会
I do.
它有名字吗？
Does it have a name?
守誓剑
Oathkeeper.
我的剑叫缝衣针
Mine's Needle.
好名字
Good name.
谁教你武艺的？
Who taught you how to fight?
我父亲
My father.
我父亲从不愿教
Mine never wanted to.
他说那是男孩子学的
Said fighting was for boys.
我父亲也这么说
Mine said the same.
但我还是跟男孩子们打
But I kept fighting the boys anyway.
还一直都输
Kept losing.
最后我父亲说, “如果你非得打,
Finally my father said, "If you're going to do it,
就好好打吧。”
you might as well do it right."
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
七神保佑
Seven blessings.
我是塔斯的布雷妮 这是波德瑞克
I'm Brienne of Tarth. This is Podrick Payne.
你想怎样？
You want something?
那是“猎狗”桑铎·克里冈
That's Sandor Clegane. The Hound.
你是艾莉亚·史塔克
You're Arya Stark.
我问你想怎样
I asked if you wanted something.
我向你母亲发过誓 要带你回家
I swore to your mother I would bring you home to her.
我母亲死了
My mother's dead.
我知道
I know.
我真希望当时能在身边保护她
I wish I could have been there to protect her.
你不是北方人
You're not a northerner.
我不是 但我立下了神圣的誓言要保护她
No, but I swore a sacred vow to protect her.
那你为什么没有保护好她？
Why didn't you?
她命我押送詹姆·兰尼斯特回君临
She commanded me to bring Jaime Lannister back to King's Landing.
你被兰尼斯特收买了
You're paid by the Lannisters.
你是来杀我领赏的
You're here for the bounty on me.
我没有被兰尼斯特收买
I'm not paid by the Lannisters.
没有吗？
No?
那你那把漂亮的剑
Fancy sword you've got there.
是打哪儿来的？
Where'd you get it?
兰尼斯特的金子我可成天见
I've been looking at Lannister gold all my life.
说啊 塔斯他妈的布蕾妮
Go on, Brienne of fucking Tarth.
你敢说这不是兰尼斯特的金子
Tell me that's not Lannister gold.
詹姆·兰尼斯特给了我这把剑
Jaime Lannister gave me this sword.
血门距此不过十里
The Bloody Gate is 10 miles.
我曾以旧神的名义对你母亲发誓
I swore to your mother by the old gods--
我才不在乎你的誓言
I don't care what you swore.
- 艾莉亚！ - 你听到她说的了
- Arya! -  You heard the girl.
- 她不会跟你走的 - 她会的
- She's not coming with you. - She is.
你真是听不懂人话
You're not a good listener.
瓦雷利亚钢剑？
That Valyrian steel?
我一直想要把瓦雷利亚钢剑玩玩
I always wanted some Valyrian steel.
跟我走吧 艾莉亚 我带你去安全的地方
Come with me, Arya. I'll take you to safety.
安全的地方？ 那他妈是哪儿？
Safety? Where the fuck's that?
她鹰巢城的姨妈死了 她妈妈死了
Her aunt in the Eyrie is dead. Her mother's dead.
她爸死了 她哥哥也死了
Her father's dead. Her brother's dead.
临冬城成了乱石堆
Winterfell is a pile of rubble.
没有什么地方是安全的 你个蠢婊子
There is no safety, you dumb bitch.
你连这都不明白
You don't know that by now,
你还怎么保护她
you're the wrong one to watch over her.
这么说
And that's what you're doing?
你是在保护她？
Watching over her?
对 老子在保护她
Aye, that's what I'm doing.
我并不想杀你 爵士
I have no wish to kill you, Ser.
我不是骑士
I'm not a knight.
艾莉亚！
Arya!
- 她在哪儿？ - 她刚才还在这儿
- Where is she? -  She was just here.
你怎么不看着她？
Why weren't you watching her?
我在看你 我觉得你可能会需要帮助
I was watching you. I thought you might need some help.
哪条路 波德？她沿着哪条路走了？
Which way, Pod? Which way did she go?
我想是这边
I think that way.
艾莉亚！
Arya!
你还在这儿？
You still here?
壮婊子救了你
Big bitch saved you.
我不需要被谁救
I don't need saving.
对 你不需要 你是个真正的杀手
No, not you. You're a real killer.
你有你的水之舞
With your water dancing
和缝衣针
and your Needle.
你要死了吗？
You gonna die?
除非这石头后面还藏着个学士
Unless there's a maester hiding behind that rock,
没错
aye,
我完了
I'm done.
我要把你活剥了喝血
I'd skin you alive for wine.
我他妈的不渴
Fuck water.
到头来被个娘们杀了
Killed by a woman.
这下你高兴了
I bet you like that.
走吧
Go on,
去跟上她
go after her.
她会帮助你的
She'll help you.
你一个人的话
Going it alone,
一天都撑不下去
you won't last a day out there.
我会比你撑得久的
I'll last longer than you.
记得心脏在哪儿吗？
You remember where the heart is?
干它吧
Fuck it.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
来吧 小姑娘
Go on, girl.
你的名单又能少一个名字了
Another name off your list.
你得信守承诺
You kept promising me.
我砍了你的朋友 屠夫的儿子
I cut down your butcher's boy.
那红毛小子
The ginger.
他哀求我慈悲
He was begging for mercy.
“求你了 爵士 不要杀我
"Please, Ser. Please don't kill me.
求你了 求你了”
Please, please."
那屠夫崽子的血把我的马浇了个遍
Bled all over my horse.
鞍子上的恶臭几个星期都不散
Saddle stunk of butcher's boy for weeks.
还有你姐姐
And your sister.
你漂亮的姐姐
Your pretty sister.
黑水河烧起来那天晚上
I should have taken her.
我应该掳走她
That night the Blackwater burned.
我真他妈的应该破了她的处
I should have fucked her bloody.
至少还能有个快活的回忆
At least I'd have one happy memory.
非得我求你吗？
Do I have to beg you?
动手吧
Do it.
杀了我
Kill me.
杀了我！
Kill me!
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
噢 来吧 你个婊子养的
Oh, get on with it, you son of a whore.
你是在说咱妈么？
Is that any way to speak about our mother?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你觉得我在干什么？
What do you think I'm doing?
港口里有艘帆船等着开往自由贸易城邦
A galley's waiting in the bay bound for the Free Cities.
- 谁在帮你？ - 瓦里斯
- Who's helping you? - Varys.
- 瓦里斯？ - 你也没众叛亲离到那地步嘛
- Varys? - You have more friends than you thought.
这台阶顶上有一扇锁着的门
There's a locked door at the top of the stairs.
敲两下 然后再敲两下
Knock on it twice, then twice again.
瓦里斯会开门的
Varys will open.
我就当这是道别了
I suppose this is good-bye, then.
永别了 弟弟
Farewell, little brother.
詹姆
Jaime.
谢谢你救我
Thank you for my life.
快走吧
Quickly now.
泰温？
Tywin?
我的狮子
My lion.
雪伊
珊莎的侍女 小恶魔的情人
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
提利昂
Tyrion.
把十字弓放下
Put down the crossbow.
谁把你放了？
Who released you?
我想是你哥哥
Your brother, I expect.
他还是太爱你了
He always had a soft spot for you.
走吧 我们去我房间里聊
Come, we'll go and talk in my chambers.
你就想在这说是吧？
This is how you want to speak to me, hmm?
你总是以羞辱父亲为乐
Shaming your father has always given you pleasure.
终我一生
All my life
你一直想让我死
you've wanted me dead.
是的
Yes.
但你拒绝去死
But you refused to die.
我只能尊重你
I respect that.
甚至钦佩你
Even admire it.
你所拥有的一切都是努力得来的
You fight for what's yours.
我绝不会让他们处决你
I'd never let them execute you.
你不就是怕这个么？
Is that what you fear?
我绝不会让伊林·派恩砍你的脑袋
I'll never let Ilyn Payne take your head.
你是兰尼斯特家族的人
You're a Lannister.
是我的儿子
You're my son.
我爱她
I loved her.
谁？
Who?
雪伊
Shae.
噢 提利昂
Oh, Tyrion.
- 把十字弓放下 - 我杀了她
- Put down that crossbow. - I murdered her.
亲手杀了她
With my own hands.
- 这无关紧要 - 无关紧要？
- It doesn't matter. - Doesn't matter?
她只是个妓女
She was a whore.
- 你敢再说一遍那个词…… - 不然呢？
- Say that word again... -  And what?
你就会在茅厕里杀了你的亲生父亲？
You'll kill your own father in the privy?
不
No.
你是我儿子
You're my son.
好了 废话说得够多了
Now, enough of this nonsense.
我是你儿子 你却判我死刑
I am your son and you sentenced me to die.
你明知道我没有毒死乔佛里
You knew I didn't poison Joffrey,
但你还是判我死刑
but you sentenced me all the same.
- 为什么？ - 够了
- Why? - Enough.
回我房间去细谈
We'll go back to my chambers
这里太不像话
and speak with some dignity.
我不会回去 她在那儿
I can't go back there. She's in there.
你怕一个死了的妓女？
You're afraid of a dead whore?
你射中我了
You shot me.
你不是我儿子
You're no son of mine.
我是你儿子
I am your son.
我永远是你儿子
I have always been your son.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
你做了什么？
What have you done?
快来
Quickly.
相信我 朋友 我会带你远走高飞
Trust me, my friend. I brought you this far.
我想见见船长
I want to see the captain.
我就是
You're seeing him.
我想北上去长城
I want to go north to the Wall.
不可能
No, you don't.
我可以付钱
I can pay.
北境除了冰雪、战乱和海盗以外什么都没有
There is nothing in the North but ice and war and pirates.
我不住舱房什么的 求求你
I wouldn't need a cabin. Please.
我可以擦洗甲板
I could work scrubbing the floors.
我不会去北境的 孩子 我要回家
I'm not going north, child. I'm going home.
- 你的家在哪儿？ - 自由贸易城邦布拉佛斯
- Where's home? - The Free City of Braavos.
等等 我还有别的
Wait. I have something else.
再多的银子也没用
More silver won't make a difference.
不是银子 是枚铁币
It's not silver. It's iron.
这……
This...
你是怎么——
How did you--
凡人皆有一死
Valar morghulis.
凡人皆需侍奉
Valar dohaeris.
来吧 你会有一间舱房
Of course, you shall have a cabin.
衣柜字幕组出品
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？欢迎登陆 冰火中文维基 查询
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
本期关键字
泰温·兰尼斯特  雪伊  曼斯·雷德  桑铎·克里冈 “凡人皆有一死”
衣柜字幕组成员巡礼（排名不分先后）
翻译组：Barossa 艾莉娅的缝衣针 盗墓奸尸 麻绳力攻 小愤青菜 reasno 猇亭将 Rubilacxe 波隆史铎克渥斯 Bran的夏天 陌客之子 唐朝栗子 梅丽珊卓 北落师门 夜俱 拉拉兄控凯冯 为万世开百事 千耳 imzxz1051 舟生也喜欢下雨天
校对组：pksunking 夏大猫子 泰温公爵 拉拉兄控凯冯 Barrosa 盗墓奸尸 小恶魔透明子 北落师门 处女做的玫瑰永不破
衣柜字幕组成员巡礼（排名不分先后）
特效组：加文·维斯特林 poplar Jeremy 窝鹏偏逢连夜雪
监制组：临冬城的狮子 北落师门 托曼
总策划：baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问：屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
感谢又一季大家对于衣柜组的支持，衣柜字幕组与您相约第五季！